ninecolours.com 2018-04-05

# Privacy Policy

We respect the trust you place on [ninecolours.com](https://www.ninecolours.com/). We are committed to protect all information that you share with us. We insist upon the highest standards for secure transactions and customer information privacy. We follow stringent procedures to help protect the confidentiality, security, and integrity of data stored on our systems. Please go through our following privacy policy. Please note that our privacy policy is subject to change at any time without notice and by updating this page. To make sure you are aware of any changes, please review this policy periodically.   

Throughout this privacy policy references to ‘website’ mean ‘[ninecolours.com](https://www.ninecolours.com/)’ and references to “you” mean any person submitting any data to us or our agent or this website.

**1\. Collection of Personally Identifiable and other Information:**

If you do nothing during your visit to our website but browse through the website, read pages, or download information, We automatically collect and store the following information about your visit. Your web browser software transmits most of this information to us. This information does not identify you personally: (i) The numeric IP address from which you access the Site;(ii) The type of browser and operating system used to access the Site; (iii) The date and time you access the Site; (iv)The pages you visit, including graphics loaded from each page and other documents you download, such as PDF files and word processing documents; and (v) If you linked to the Site from another web site, the address of that web site.

We use the above information to help us make our website more useful to you and visitors like you.

We need to use ‘cookies’ on the website to enhance the user shopping experience and avoid multiple logins or password authentication requests. A "cookie" is a tiny text file that a web site can place on your computer's hard drive in order to collect information about your activities on the site. cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. However, this may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website. Please note that the cookies we use for our website or email campaigns do not store personally identifiable information about you.

In addition to the information specified above, you may choose to provide certain information for online shopping on this website, including the following.

  * When you register (log in), you supply your email address and a password. This allows us to provide you access to your account every time you visit our Website.
  * Before completing your first purchase, we also ask you for your name, phone number/ mobile number, email, billing and shipping addresses. This information, along with details pertaining to your bank account or credit card or debit card or other payment instruments is necessary to fulfill your order.
  * Other content and data that you provide while using the website, for example, blogs, discussion boards, chat messages, membership of mailing lists and other data, documents and images stored on our servers.

In addition, from time to time, we may ask you for additional information.

We only collect your Personal Information to conduct our business and to enable us to deliver and improve our Services. We do not sell your Personal Information to any third party or otherwise trade on it.

**2\. Use of information:**

We use personal information to provide the services you request. We use your personal information to resolve disputes; troubleshoot problems; help promote a safe service; collect fees owed; measure consumer interest in our products and services, inform you about online and offline offers, products, services, and updates; customize your experience; detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity; enforce our terms and conditions; and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection. In our efforts to continually improve our product and service offerings, we collect and analyze data about our users' activity on our website. We identify and use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information.  We use this data to tailor your experience at our site, providing you with content that we think you might be interested in and to display content according to your preferences.

We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process.

We may disclose personal information to law enforcement offices, third party rights owners, or others in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: enforce our Terms or Privacy Policy; respond to claims that an advertisement, posting or other content violates the rights of a third party; or protect the rights, property or personal safety of our users or the general public

**3\. Use of services**

Your use of all services on the website and your provision of information in connection with these services are purely voluntary. You will always have the option of whether to perform the transaction and provide this information. However, in order to open an online service account or perform a service transaction, you will be required to provide some personal information. Whether to perform the transaction is up to you.

If you choose to provide us with personal information, we will use that information to respond to your message and to help us get you the product or information you have requested. You may choose to subscribe to our online newsletter describing new services and updates on the site. You may unsubscribe at any time.

We may transfer our databases containing your personal information if we sell our business or part of it.

**4\. Security**

We take the integrity of the information and systems that we maintain very seriously. As such, we have instituted security measures for all information systems under our control so that information will not be lost, misused or altered.

For website security purposes and to ensure that our Services remain available to all users, we employ software programs to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage. Notwithstanding anything stated above, we reserve the right to use information from these sources to help identify an individual or prosecute malicious use or misuse of the website.

Your account information is password-protected for your privacy and security. In certain areas, as with credit card transactions, our Site uses industry-standard secure socket layer (SSL) encryption to protect data transmissions.

Any of your information which you provide when you use certain Services and are to an open, public environment or forum including (without limitation) any blog, community or discussion board, is not confidential, does not constitute Personal Information, and is not subject to protection under Privacy Policy. Since such public environments are accessible by third parties, it is possible that third parties may collect and collate and use such information for their own purposes. You should accordingly be careful when deciding to share any of your Personal Information in such public environments.

Ninecolours.com may use various outside agencies (third party service providers) to make our Website operate. For example, we may use third parties to host our Website, operate various features made available on our Website, send emails, SMS, analyze data, provide search results and links, and assist in fulfilling your orders. We may exchange information with third parties for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Some of these third parties may need access to your information in order to make the services provided through our Website work. Information will only be disclosed to these service providers on a need-to-know basis, and they will only be permitted to use such information for the purpose of providing the particular services provided by such entities in connection with our Website. We seek to protect your rights of privacy on systems and this website ([ninecolours.com](https://www.ninecolours.com/)) controlled by us, but we are not liable for any unauthorised or unlawful disclosures of your personal and confidential information made by third parties who are not subject to our control. You should take note that the information and privacy policies of our business partners, advertisers, sponsors or other sites to which we provide hyperlinks, may be different from ours.

**5\. Grievances and Redressal:**

We are committed to promptly address any grievances that you might have in connection with our use of any information that you provide us. Accordingly, you may communicate any grievances that you might have by e-mailing, phoning, us at contact numbers provided here [Contact Us](https://www.ninecolours.com/contact-us).
